Paripás Viktor

O Solna | +46724516263 | viktorparipas@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn

Summary

I am a backend developer with 7 years of total software engineering experience with an engineering and math background, passionate about machine learning and statistics. Looking for remote opportunities.

Skills and technologies

| • | Programming languages | Python JavaScript C++ MATLAB |
|---|----------------------------------|--------------------------------------------|
| • | Web development | Django Flask Django REST Vue.js |
| • | Data analysis & machine learning | scikit-learn NumPy Pandas PyTorch |
| • | Cloud, containers & databases | Heroku AWS PostgreSQL MySQL Docker |

Professional experience

Kognity AB

Full-Stack Engineer

Aug 2022-

Stockholm, SE (Remote)

- Implemented features of teaching & learning platform, across the stack (Django & Vue.js) with backend focus, such as secure image upload or activity sheets
- Led backend projects such as a question service as dedicated responsible individual, leading to a more maintainable, decoupled and simpler codebase
- Revised database model architecture to decrease response times at certain endpoints by 90% (Django & PostgreSQL)
- Implemented event tracking for data analytics with Google Pubsub and Mixpanel
- Drafted detailed REST API guidelines and started migration of existing API to be compliant
- Wrote and acted upon blameless post-mortems to improve code quality, safety net and ways of working, to reach an uptime of 99.99%
- Acted as interim tech lead for a squad of five developers

Prorenata AB

Senior Backend Developer

2020 - 2022

Stockholm, SE (Remote)

- Developed the REST API and backend services of cloud-based student healthcare administration platform Prorenata Journal in Django/DRF
- Improved system availability and response time by optimizing database transactions, identifying and resolving slow queries in Django/MySQL
- Implemented the backend of a new in-house customer support app to ensure storing of user data within the EU
- Implemented a patient portal with BankID integration increasing number of DAU by 100%
- Acting as release manager, responsible for deploying both patch updates and major releases

ÅF Digital Solutions AB

Software Engineer (Consultant)

2018 - 2020

Solna / Södertälje, SE

Assignment for Powertrain & Control Development @ Scania

- Developed a web application to fetch and display the CI build warnings grouped by module and severity for 200+ developers. (Flask, SQLAlchemy)
- Developed tools for model-based design, in Matlab and Python

Assignment for Connected Diagnostics @ Scania

 Worked in a client team to develop an on-board application enabling the sending of over-the-air updates to truck ECUs in C++. Practiced test-driven development and implemented onion architecture model.

Robert Bosch Kft.

Software Engineer

2017 - 2018

Budapest, HU

• Developed trajectory planning and control algorithms for driver assistance and autonomous driving systems

AVL Autókut Kft.

Software Engineer

2016 - 2017

Budapest, HU

• Developed diesel exhaust aftertreatment system functions in MATLAB/Simulink

Analysis Engineer

• Performed multi-body simulation and NVH analysis of internal combustion engine powertrain components such as conrods or crankshafts in Abaqus and Excite.

Education

Luleå University of Technology

2022 - 2023

Computer Science and Engineering (MSc) - Applied AI; Completed 57.0 ECTS

KTH Royal Institute of Technology

2015 - 2016

Stockholm, SE

Master's degree project at the Department of Solid Mechanics (Exchange studies)

2010 - 2016

MSc in Mechanical Engineering - Applied Mechanics

120 ECTS

Distinguished Scholarship of the Republic (top 0.8%), 2 years in a row

GPA 4.87/5

BSc in Mechanical Engineering - Mechanical Development

210 ECTS GPA 4.67/5

Language proficiency

Hungarian

Native proficiency

English

Full professional proficiency (TOEFL level C2, 2021)

Swedish

Professional working proficiency (SVA2 level C1, 2021)

French

Limited working proficiency (level C1, 2015)

German

Limited working proficiency

Hobbies & interests

Playing the drums, mixology, traveling and learning new languages